Alright, here is the second version, version
0.2, where I'm already doing the mapping
of the image.
So, if I click here to open the
software, it will open here, will load
the first tab of the device, but I'll
load that last workspace that we
had already made.
Here is the last workspace with all the
devices from this image, which is
practically the same as the one there. I
tweaked the one in EVE a bit, but the
equipment is here.
So, the secret here now to do the mapping is
a JSON file with the coordinates of each
piece of equipment, width and height.
To save time, I dropped this into the AI,
and asked it to give me this file.
It gave me this file here, with all
the devices and the coordinates of each
one. So here is the list of all of them.
And with this list, what do I do with it?
With this list I come here to the Map
button, or I can also come this way,
right?
Load Topology Map, so I load that
file the AI gave me, this topology JSON
that I saved here. I'll load this
file, I'll zoom in here, I'll zoom in on the
image, so here you see I'm already
hovering the mouse over it,
and I already see the reference to click on the
equipment.
However, the coordinates the AI gave me
are a bit off, so I'll need to
edit those coordinates.
So I have this editor button here.
When I click here, it allows me to
edit the coordinates.
And so, I'll fix this little guy here.
I come here, place it here, set the width
and height however I want, ok, and I keep doing
this for the others, doing the same for
the others.
So, I keep doing this, then I come here and
save,
and after making the file I made
here, I'll overwrite it, ok, done. I'll
go back to the tabs. So there I mapped
this one, I come here and click on it, on
SW4, it went to the SW4 tab. On R8,
it goes to the R8 tab. Here on S7,
it's off, I haven't mapped it yet,
it goes to the S7 tab. And here we
have another catch — there's an S7 lower
here, so there's an S7 up here, an SW7 on
top and an SW7 below, a lower here.
When I press here, it does nothing.
This one goes to SW7.
If I look at the list, I have two SW7,
but why is that?
Because here in EVE, when I told it
to import, it imported exactly the name
that's here.
However, if I click here on the first one, it
went to the first SW7.
If I click on the second, it goes to the
second.
Why?
Because here it goes by IP and port,
instead of mapping by name.
So if I look at this first one,
it has the final port 85, and on this
second one, it has the final port 90.
So from EVE to here, it gets mapped
correctly, but here since it's by name, and
in order not to repeat the name, it placed SW7
here and SW7Lower here.
To avoid repeating the name, it placed this
"lower" here, but it won't do anything.
So if I'm here on number 5 and click on
"lower", it doesn't go to it.
What can I do?
Change it here to the same name.
Instead of "lower" I'll put dash 2
here.
Ok, I'll come here to my editor, I'll come
here to my editor,
came here to this little guy,
and I'll rename it dash 2, ok, it's
now dash 2, done. Now if I click here on
this one it's here, if I click on this one it's
here, it's going correctly to the tabs, it's all
correct here if I enable the editor
I keep fine-tuning these little guys, right?
I already did this in all of them, gave it some
adjustments. Some things I did in batch,
did manually, a nice quick adjustment here,
and I'll load this map that I've already
fixed here, so if I come here to
topology, there's this map of this...
then you...
load the map, and now you see it's
all correct.
If I press here, you see it has
SW11, I ended up putting SW11 and
it has no effect up there.
If I come here and change it to SW11, the
moment I click here it's already there.
Click on the router, click here, so here
I can already get a ready-made mapping,
or I ask the AI to speed up one side and then
I keep fine-tuning here. It's possible to edit the
file there with the coordinates by hand, if
it's faster. When I got it the
first time, I noticed there was a
standard offset, standard size, I
went there and did it in
a batch, one adjustment, then I came here and
did just a fine adjustment.
Turned out perfect, very good.
Here's version 0.2 with the mapping of the
devices from the image to the tabs.